okay so we always started DCI program
the same way so DCI is a where we go
teach business groups around the world
and governmental groups and we always
start the same way and I was thinking I
would like to start that way tonight
first of all I thought you guys might
like to see how we do it and then
secondly it's very important for the
text we're doing okay so bear with me
most of you have seen most of this but I
think it's necessary that were on the
same page we're speaking the same
language okay so here we go what happens
at a DCI event is oftentimes I'll start
by talking about a pen you got a pen
yeah and this is how we do it okay and
we start almost we speak to 30,000
people a year on DCI and we always start
the same way so I'll tell people I'm
going to help you understand our new
system and I'd like you to give me
answers to my questions and I often say
don't be like the executives at British
Airways that we taught and they refuse
to say anything they just sat there like
this and so don't be like that don't be
shy okay what's this thing yeah it's a
pen and if a small dog comes in here and
I waved this thing in front of the dog
what will they do
yeah they will chew it and then I say
well who's that's the dog see this as a
pen then you say no and then I say well
what does the dog see they see something
to chew and then you ask well who's
corrected the person or the dog both are
okay why yeah the dog can enjoy it and
the person can write with it there was
one person in Florida once who said
sorry your parents are there right they
insisted that the dog was wrong and that
the human wasn't right but that's just
one person out of about a hundred
thousand so yeah both are okay dog can
enjoy person can can use it to write
something now the next question is if I
put this thing here and all the darks
clout of the room and all the people go
out of the room at that time which one
is it yeah all around the world people
will go like this which means at that
point it's nothing okay and people will
say nothing okay and then so then if I
come back in the room and I walk up here
and I catch catch sight of it what does
it become at that moment
yeah because a pentagon if the dog had
come in what would it have become so
that proves something about the pen that
somehow the pen is coming from me human
nature is to believe that the pen is
coming from the pen there's a something
built into a human being when you're
born there's a veil on the eyes and on
the mind where you believe you feel that
the pen is coming from the pen but in
actuality we just demonstrated you know
indisputably that it must be coming from
you then it's useful when you teach the
pen if you have time you can say so can
I just close my eyes and and wish that
it was a big diamond and it will say if
it's coming from me can I just wish that
it was something else yes or no no yeah
you can wish but it won't change then
sometimes when I'm speaking to a
Buddhist crowd offset you can do mantras
you can say Oh money pay me home and
it's not going to change you know
there's something else forcing your mind
to see it as a pen and then that's that
you have a seed in your mind according
to Buddhism you have a seed in your mind
because at some point in the past I
shared them with Alex and when I put it
in her hand and I saw my hand open then
that planted a seed in my mind and that
seed you can call it karma or you can
just call it a mental state okay in when
we teach the CI we try to avoid Buddhist
words so we'll just say it's a mental
see so I have a mental state in my mind
I've been carrying it around since I
gave the pen to Alex maybe two weeks
later when I see this thing this green
thing then the state opens in my mind
and a small
luminous picture made of light about
this big a pen about this big comes out
of the seed the seed cracks open karma
and a small picture comes out and it it
super imposes itself on this thing then
I see a pen the dog doesn't have that
seed the doll has a seed for a cheat or
maybe they shared it a bone before I
don't know ok but they have a seed in
their mind and when their seat opens a
small picture comes out those pictures
are coming out at the rate of 65 per
second it's too fast to see your reality
is like a video on the Internet the
video is 24 frames per second your
reality is 65 frames per second because
but it also includes smell taste touch
you know yours is more rich but it's
still just still pictures too coming out
of your mind seats camara mine if you
meditate a lot you can see the seeds
open and you can see the pictures come
out and after that you believe all this
stuff forever but you have to meditate
on a regular basis to see that ok so
then at a DCI program will say that
means that everything around you is
coming from you so the this school the
microphone the words I'm saying the
person next to you it's all coming out
of season your mind see so in theory you
could make things the way you want them
to be if you could learn how to plant
seeds okay so in theory you could have
anything you want you could have
beautiful relationships you could have
financial success you could have good
health you could have a peaceful mind
your world would be more beautiful in
theory if you understand how to plant a
seed
so then I'll tell people the second
thing we do in DCI the first night is we
say so now I'm going to teach you how to
plant a seed there's four steps to
planting seed then I'll say Scott do you
have $100 bill we have a special fund
for this expenses no it's okay okay okay
that's enough
then I'll take somebody in the audience
okay I'll just go up Mirabai is that
okay okay you have to stand up and I'll
just pick somebody at random in the
audience and I'll tell people I'm going
to show you how to plant the seeds from
which your reality come from okay and
there's four steps to planting a seed
and I try to take somebody in the back
that I don't know and who looks like
they could use $100 and you know I try
not to pick a friend of mine somebody I
hang out with because it gets kind of
anyway so I'll say step number one and
these come from the fourth chapter that
I'll be double crochet okay it's a she's
some pejorative it's very famous so step
number one you have to decide what you
want
so tonight I'm actually planting a
thousand dollars I have a hundred
dollars but I would like to change it
into a thousand dollars okay so nowadays
when we teach it overseas like we just
got back from Russia will tell them this
is not a demonstration this is real this
is how I make my salary you know and
because people will chase me with the
hundred dogs they try to give it back to
me and I'll say no don't mess it up
you know I'm making money tonight okay
so so number one what do I want
what's your goal and I want a thousand
dollars okay I have a hundred I want a
thousand No step number two what yeah I
have to ask her I need a partner you
need a seed planning partner
you cannot plant a seed without a
partner you cannot make an echo without
a wall okay so I asked her meerabai we
do you like to make some money tonight
for free she's like I never had anybody
refuse
okay third step it's actually planting
the Karma
okay and I asked you to raise their hand
up and it's you know now there's our
last people in the audience to to video
it while we're doing it and they take it
home and watching so there'll be a
thousand people with their phone
recording it and then they take it home
and they use it all week Jenny so I put
in their hand
I close their hands now watch one two
three days and when I see my own hand
open my mind records it and then that
becomes an impression on my mind son
skarner right and then in about two
hours in the subconscious that becomes a
karmic steal okay that becomes a seed
for $1,000 okay then I waved goodbye
goodbye thank you and that's the second
thing we always do it the start of a
decent song then I say hit somebody in
the audience who's clever we'll say you
didn't do four steps you just did three
and I'll say well yeah that's the
important thing that if you don't know
step number four that thing could take
years to open and there's two problems
with that number one I don't make my
thousand dollars number two then I don't
believe the system because I didn't get
something
man I gave $100 and nothing happened you
see I mean so it's important that we do
step number four which makes the seat
open faster if the seat opens to the
next few days then I'll get some faith
in this in this system you see anything
and if the seat doesn't open in the next
few days I will think it doesn't work
you see so most people don't know the
fourth step of a karma is that you must
put water on it it's like a regular seat
and the water is supplied through a
special meditation that traditionally we
do before as you go to bed and you just
relax and you lay down on your cushion
sometimes I'll do a full Lotus up here
and tell people I'll say oh you think
this is meditation right that you have
to do this and then you have the guy and
it's funny 'no sin a business suit and
then they'll say i'll say no no this is
a different thing this is difficult you
just relax and you you lay back on your
pillow as you go to bed and you just
think about the meerabhai and how she
looked in the moment that you gave her a
hundred dollars and you enjoy how she
looked and that enjoyment sense
productivity and then the seat will open
faster ok so you guys know this whole
step so that's two things we'll always
do before a DCI program we'll go through
the pin and we'll go through the four
steps and it's important to do it
tonight
because of where we're going tonight
with their teaching there's a third
demonstration that we often do at this
point to demonstrate a lot of different
principles and it's called the two
husbands in the kitchen it has spread
all over the world I ran into like six
people doing it in Romania and
it's some guy put a video online anyway
it's crazy so I'm gonna do the two
husband's in the kitchen okay
it's a joke that in Singapore one night
twelve hundred people came and a French
guy came up to me afterwards he was very
angry and he said you getting old you
know as I know he said well you you
taught the pan last year and you taught
those four steps last year you forgot
you know I said no I didn't forget I
taught them again here then he's like
why I said because you're not successful
yet I have to keep teaching them if you
want me to stop teaching them when
you're happy and successful and you have
a beautiful family now I can stop
teaching the pen okay
so anyway here's the third demonstration
that we always do I need two husbands
Scott's gonna be one where it's gonna be
one okay and these seem a little bit
silly but we're gonna demonstrate the
importance of them shortly okay so I'm a
normal working woman I am married to a
guy I have two kids will you guys be my
kids okay and I'm not yet so I have two
kids I have a job for an international
company you know I often work late and I
have to do the cooking and I have to do
the groceries and I have to take the
kids to school and I have to make the
money this is modern times you know the
husband used to do something right so
you know I'm coming out of work one
night and the boss grabs me and says I
need you tomorrow you know but they say
it in that way which makes it clear that
they're gonna fire you if you don't come
in tomorrow early okay so they're like
don't forget you have to come in early
tomorrow
right like one hour early and then
you're like yes boss okay I'll do it but
in your mind you're thinking all this is
going to be so difficult to coordinate
with my kids and get everybody dressed
and get them to school and I don't
really it's gonna be really hard you
know so you go to your kids their
bedroom and you say look mommy has to go
tomorrow early one hour and could you
guys just be ready have your pyjamas on
have your homework done you know I'll
dress you agree yeah they agree right
okay next day you wake up an hour early
and you come into their room and they
are fighting and they are jumping on the
bed and they are screaming and they
don't have their clothes on they still
have their pajamas on and the homeworks
all over the floor and you say you are
the stupidest kids in Sedona okay and
they start crying because they heard you
right who else heard you yeah you heard
you okay
and that's Karma you say how karma is
planted in your mind is you must see
yourself do something and you must hear
yourself do something or you must hear
yourself think something right so every
word I say you are it goes like this and
it enters my eardrum and it makes an
impression on my mind okay and then
after about two hours that becomes a
currency next week I'm coming home I
bought the groceries you know I picked
the kids up already and I'm tired I'm
exhausted
yeah and I'm really tired and I'm coming
home and I'm thinking I starting to
wonder why I have a husband like you
know but he there's one thing he always
does he gives me hugs
he gives me really nice hugs you know so
it's kind of worth it
you know that's the one thing he does
which is good you know so I come home I
tired I'm looking forward to a hug I
open the kitchen door and I go you're
stupid then I I get upset you know like
I didn't do anything because he's stupid
you know I just opened the door I didn't
even say anything yet you know I didn't
do anything
am i right is it right is it right that
I didn't do anything
yeah yeah right then I didn't do
anything but last week I planted the
seed right so it's not correct to say
you didn't do anything right now how can
you prove that your husband is correct
when your husband calls me stupid for no
reason at all yeah he's fun yeah I'm not
stupid you're stupid
why well who will hear it you will hear
it and he won't plant a seed in your
mind then next week with the kids this
seed will open right again and the kids
will be back and then you get mad at the
kids then you plant another stick and
then you go back to the husband and
you're stupid and it's like this you see
I get mad at them he creates it creates
him not stupid I said no I'm not stupid
you're stupid
and then that fantasy they're bad next
week
yeah and it goes like this okay it goes
like this alright so how can the wife
break the cycle then become go to the
toilet look in the mirror and say
okay got it but don't answer him okay
then sometimes I like to tell all the
wise in the audience look between you
and me all husbands are stupid but don't
say it because then your kids will act
up next week so just be chill you know
just calm down okay now at this point I
make a joke I say you're supposed to ask
me why I have to happen okay like then
that usually people start laughing so
you know weren't you wondering why I
have two husbands in the kitchen okay
now these are two different husbands in
the kitchen there's always two husbands
in the kitchen okay always there's two
husbands in your house okay there's
always two okay
but they're different this one we can
call came from yelling at the kids this
one came from my feet okay got it
this one came from my students got it
this one we can call him I didn't do
anything okay this is that I didn't do
anything husband all right here's the I
mean do anything husband and here's the
husband who came from my C's when they
opened like the pen when I walked in the
room okay so now when you teach it you
think now I'll tell you something
amazing one of these husbands really
exists and one of these husbands doesn't
exist who's who this one comes from
seeds this one comes from my Steve does
he exist yeah yeah this one exists okay
this one I keep tweeting I just walk in
and yelling does he exist and then if
you want to be precise what the Buddha
said was doesn't exist tonight didn't
exist in all the time up to now and
could never
exist in the future this husband I
didn't do anything husband is an
impossibility complete impossibility
okay got it now if you want to go deeper
and we were in Ukraine last year and
it's happy there it's happy there there
at war there are refugees in the
audience from their own country from
from 3 hours away
you know and it's heavily there you know
and you say you know can we when you get
angry at the husband okay when you get
angry that he called you stupid right
which one are you angry this one who
come from your seat you cannot get angry
at him why you understand that when he
yells at you it's coming from you it's
your fault it's impossible to understand
him and be angry at him at the same time
it's not possible if you understand that
he came from yelling at the kids
you just feel some kind of regret you're
like oh I should stop yelling at the
kids but you don't get angry at him
you're sorry for him you're sorry that
he's there but you don't get it you
don't blame him because you're you're
the only person to blame you understand
that so you don't get angry okay but
when you do get angry it has to be a
Scott okay when you do get angry it has
to be at one and a husband that you
think isn't your fault it must be it's
impossible to get angry at this one
because you understand he's coming from
you but it's natural to get angry at
this one because you think he decided to
yell on you you think it's him who
decided to yell you don't believe it's
coming from you okay guarding now when
you get angry you get angry at this one
but this one doesn't
even exist and it's the same with all
enemies all enemies in the world
corporate enemies racial enemies
religious enemies national enemies you
know and if you live long enough right
commander
if you live long enough you know when I
was young the enemy was the Germans and
then it was the Vietnamese Oh Koreans
Koreans then it was the Vietnamese and
then it was the Russians and there was
the you know the Arabs and then it was
the Chinese and when you live over 60
every 10 years the garments which is the
enemy then you get suspicious after my
right but I thought the Vietnamese were
the enemy
no no they're friends but you know and
every there's a different group you're
supposed to hate every 10 years okay but
the thing is ok so every war that was
ever fought like in the UK this was
having we taught it in Ukrainian people
are like you know and every enemy that
your hate doesn't mean they don't even
exist 100 million people died in World
War two by an enemy who didn't exist you
see I mean and then people are okay so
those are the three things now for the
Buddhists in the audience okay let's
let's let's confuse things with Buddhist
terminology let's load up these long
words that confuse people
so nobody understands okay so first one
where's the dependent origination here
yeah the the the wheel started here
twelve links right started here
and what's that called you can call us
on samsara
so sauna okay you can call it the wheel
of mind or you can call it dependent
origination in war you can call it cause
and effect okay so that's Carson sex
that's dependent origination that sound
Sara and that's the Wheel of Life and
there's no other Wheel of Life it's not
a painting and it's not a Buddhist
philosophy right independent originate
dependent this eight silver work the
wheel it's it how often do you have a
Wheel of Life
how often do you set a Wheel of Life
into motion no I mean a couple of times
a day maybe a couple times an hour
you are doing something that that starts
these wheels so it's not like if you get
reborn in the hell room you just finish
started a new wheel it's not like that
you are spinning off new wheels with
your kids every ten minutes you see and
then they spin off other wheel sin and
son Cyrus are going like that now where
is the emptiness here no in this kitchen
story where's the interior yeah the fact
that he doesn't exist is emptiness okay
there's no other emptiness okay
and dienes everything you ever heard of
our emptiness is silly and you can't use
it and it has no relevance to your life
okay close your eyes think about nothing
stare at black things for a long time
watch your thoughts come and go in your
mind these had nothing to do it
emptiness okay emptiness means he's he's
not there and he never was there okay
what's gotcha where's the gotcha gotcha
means what is the emptiness empty of
what's the thing that doesn't exist
when you say emptiness emptiness means
something you thought was there is not
there
that's emptiness whoo where's the
emptiness here I'm sorry who's the
gotcha yeah it's him okay
he's the imaginary thing that isn't
there okay guy very important emptiness
means emptiness of something right it's
him he is the emptiness of him okay
that's the gotcha now where's the
Nirvana
where's Navara in this story come on
here in the bathrooms pretty good yeah I
always say that yeah
definition in Tibetan yeah and then
develop opposite some tango it's when
you start getting angry because you
understand where things are coming up
that's the definition of Nirvana okay so
when she goes like this and she stops
and she pauses then she she broke link
number 1 in the Wheel of Life she
attacked Marika avidya ignorance and
she's she's she's shutting down the
wheel okay and that leads to Nirvana
that's nirvana okay got it if you have a
lot of time and you want to get fancy
where it's the Four Noble Truths here
where's the for hard truth choose number
one what this is the first teaching
Buddha ever gets I'm sure all these
Buddhist know what's the first one
you're all things are suffering where is
this suffering here twenty years others
is not fun to be yoga okay that's the
truth of suffering wait that's not a
truth that's a sound
shouldn't it be truth for truth should
be a statement right
all things are suffering is that the
first trip of the four tooth is it or
not no it's the thing it refers to
okay got it the four truths are four
facts they don't mean
this is that it's not a statement
there's not four statements as to
fortunes that's not that's a mistake
okay
burning your hand is the first noble
truth you got it
it's not like you have to stand there
and say I declare that my finger hurts
that's that's not the first truth okay
the first truth is when the husband yo
okay second truth what's the cause of
this unit yeah y'all you have two kids
planning good okay
what's the third truth here there it's
possible to break this cycle it's
possible to end it when when she refuses
to answer
and what's the pop yeah the past means
really literally potts means understand
okay when she when he yells and she
remembers the talk tonight and she
doesn't respond okay then that's the
part that is the part so in one incident
in the kitchen you have all of Buddhism
but correctly you know relate to
somebody's real bar and that's what
Buddhism was supposed to be I told Scott
the other day
this is Buddhism you know we try not to
be Buddhist in the DCI programs but but
not being Buddhist is brewed in them you
see to teach someone not in your bag is
the path to Nirvana okay so you can
teach Buddhism without mentioning
Buddhism and and maybe it's more
effective you know I don't know 30,000
people come in here maybe it's a better
way you know I don't know okay sit down
you thank you
okay now the problem with this teaching
so we're gonna do a teaching it's by the
first punch in llama
okay there's two big llamas into that
when it's called Dalai Lama when it's
called pension llama and traditionally
they kind of rotate so when the Dalai
Lama gets old the pension Lamas young
and when the pension mom is old
the die mom is young and they kind of
take care of each other
traditionally so the first pension mama
lived about four hundred years ago and
his name was lost I'm Chucky Johnson
he's on your cover of your reading and
he was an unbelievable great Lama I like
that he was a poet I I enjoy his poetry
aloud and he was an activist he did a
lot of retreats one time he was in
retreat and he got a note from his
attendant that said there's an attack
headed our way
there's an army headed our way and you
might have to break retreat you know and
then he got angry he said what kind of
army would have the insulting to break
my retreat you know and he walked out
between the two armies and he said if
you want to kill each other you gotta
kill me first
and he was already probably the most
famous Lama in Tibet at the time so
there's a beautiful story that both
sides were afraid to kill him and then
he said by the way let me talk to the
two generals you know and they came
forward and he sat down with them in
between the lines you know and he said
look being a big Lama is really
financially successful
I've got bars and bars and cold
you know I'll split it with you guys if
you stop fighting you know and he bribed
them to stop okay so I really like him
I'm really attracted to him and so he's
written great books of philosophy very
very deep
he wrote very beautiful books of
devotion mother ship all right the most
famous devotional prayer in Tibet he
wrote it we do it a couple of times when
we do retreats we do it it's the first
prayer I ever went to they were doing
not much of a prayer offering to mamas
okay but he wrote an extraordinary book
called the devil debates an angel okay
it's called dumb things um that's a
dungeon some death
shank that means to have an argument and
Donson means the devil okay and so a
devil debates an angel okay and myeloma
I started it with us and then he didn't
have a chance to finish it it seems like
it's difficult to finish and he never
finished it so we we studied it son
but I would I came back to it much later
and it's very very very beautiful and
when my personal friends asked me could
we just have a small you know intimate
gathering at the elementary school
people can drive down from Colorado and
stuff you draw you guys know we took you
took her
oh okay it's almost the same amount of
time
so I thought it would be sweet to do
with my close friends because it's a
little bit difficult okay
and we keep starting it over again
because I keep not having time to finish
it so I have a proposal tonight I'm just
gonna review the whole thing up to now
because if you're like me this teaching
has been spread out by eight years and I
always forget
last year's teaching this year and I
could just keep forging on but there is
a theme going through the whole thing
there's a there's a logic to the whole
thing so I I worked on it I worked on a
way to give it to you the whole thing
you know logical song okay and I thought
we would do that and I'd like to try to
finish it if you guys have time and we
can get back together more often maybe
I'm thinking three times a year or
something we could finish it okay
but it's up to you we can bury are we
supposed to take a break Nick yeah I'll
think about it maybe we don't take a
break okay but I wanted to give you an
idea a thought about this teaching okay
this is that classical thing where does
the devil over here a little devil this
big and there's a little angel over here
and your mind is like like I made a bet
with dr. woo he came to my house for
dinner and he's one of our main sponsors
and he said do you need anything I said
I yeah I need two million dollars by the
end of the year for thirty-one projects
you know and he's like well I'll give
you one one you know and I'll try to
find the other million then at the end
of the evening I said you're looking a
little bit
you know and he said yeah but you are
too and then I said well he said let's
have a contest during the last term who
can lose the most weight and he said if
you win I'll give you the second million
dollars you know and I was like okay you
know and then I sent all my friends to
his house with cookies and sparkles and
chocolate and then I didn't need
anything
I had a Veronica knows I had watermelon
juice for like three weeks and I was
like dizzy but I remember one night I
went to the fridge you know and I open
it up and she she keeps baking these
beautiful cakes and stuff and I'm
looking at this cake you know that she
made and this thought came into my mind
somebody's talking on this side of my
head this side of my head is like no keg
million dollars and then suddenly
there's this thought I heard it in my
mind and it said you know who's talking
over there you know and I almost I mean
my hand went out and then I'm like wait
a minute
That's not me who's talking over here
and so you get in you get these things
and you get pictures right on the
internet that they they show angel
talking over here the angels like have
watermelon juice and then the devil's
like come on your partner cooked your
nice cake you're gonna not eat it what's
what's the big deal million dollars you
know and so we all have an internal
conversation going on okay and that's
what this book is about okay and he sets
it in terms of meditation okay so anyone
who's done a three-year retreat we have
a bunch of people here who've done three
if you've done a three-year retreat you
know that during a retreat the
conversation in your mind gets extremely
detailed you know this parts talking to
this heart all day you know but during
your meditation it's particularly I
don't know that the arguments get almost
laughable it's like a comedy it's like
well huh what's the big deal but main
dogs and this was like you know and when
you meditate for a long time if you stay
quiet for three years you become very
aware of this schizophrenia in your own
mind that you have a good side of your
mind and you have a bad side okay and
according to Buddhism you cannot remove
the bad side of your mind until you
understand that things aren't there the
second husband's not even there okay
it's according to Buddhism it's
impossible to stop
anger permanently as long as you still
believe the person your anglia is even
there you see I mean you have to
understand he was never there to defeat
anger it's the only way you will ever
defeat anger okay so so this whole book
eight years of so far is the mind in
meditation hiding with the mind in
meditation okay angel and devil inside
of meditation but I think this is my big
thing tonight okay
I think that the first pension lama
wants us to to be more aware of the
inner conversation we're always having
okay
and not just in meditation you see I
think he's written a book about
meditation as a trick to get us to
realize that
we are talking to ourselves all day you
know there's always two people in your
mind talking right I mean same with you
say this I have do you have there's two
parts of your mind and they're in a
constant conversation all day right and
there's kind of a good sign in this kind
of a bad side of your mind so there's a
positive influence in your mind and
there's a negative influence of mine so
I would not call this Mahamudra
meditation I would call it internal
conversations okay they get they
intensify when you're in meditation but
they are present all the time they're
going on all day long
okay so what I wanted to suggest first
of all that you as we go through the
text
be aware that it's not just in
meditation your mind is debating all Bay
two things number one how do I get what
I want
you know like should I should I go to
his house or should I check on the
internet or should I call this person
your mind is talking to itself all day
long when you want something right and
then when you don't want something your
mind goes into the conversation again
you know well we were supposed to get
that but you know I lost my way but he
didn't give me the million dollars so
should I call him or should I chase him
or should I write an email or you know
should I carry mine
not is it more cool I don't remind them
because he might feel badly this over
way you know you know like your mind is
weighing options and you spend all day
doing one of these to you you are either
calculating what I should do you are
discussing with yourself what should I
do next today to get the things I want
but you are also debating with yourself
you know maybe I shouldn't do this or
how could you know how do I get rid of
this problem I have should I sing this
or should I say that okay got it
so your mind is already got the angel
devil going since you were born
okay this conversation internal
conversation is going on right now you
like if you're gonna take a break I
don't know if it's gonna take them back
if he takes a break should we stay I
don't know let's check the refreshments
see if they're worth it you know but you
have but it's all sounding kind of weird
I thought it's good you know your own
mind is having a conversation now okay
so there's a practice in Buddhism called
timber and fishing what's shakin what's
shakin shakin is like I had an idea
Scott we were in I forget what country
we were in Germany they had a nice
monitor in the middle they had two huge
LED monitors and then they had a very
nice monitor so I could see what I look
like you know I could kind of make my
hair you know try to not angle it you
know and sation means a monitor okay so
it says you can check how your mind is
you see it's a part of your mind that's
like a TV monitor
that's focused on you you see and you
can see if you
they're gonna take a photo group photo
great group photo so I look in the
monitor I can see if my tie straight you
know I can see if the boogers coming out
yet or not or I could say I can make it
to the end of the talk without using a
handkerchief you see I can check the
monitor to see how what gets a lot looks
like right so we all have a part of your
mind that meditators are supposed to
develop purposely which is a part of
your mind that's a monitor of how your
mind's doing so while you're in
meditation every few minutes you're
supposed to look at the monitor and sees
what's the condition of your mind okay
that's called session what's timba but
come on that's a lousy translation yep
bring it bring your mind back I like to
call it the tour guide when you go to a
museum and there's a thousand paintings
you know you go to the Louvre right it's
we went to see Rodin Museum right me and
Veronica it's nice to go with a guide
because they'll say no no come on
there's a better one in there
you know come on follow me you know I
know where the good stuff is you see it
I mean so these are two parts of your
mind that a meditate is supposed
to develop okay you're supposed to
develop it in your mind when you
meditate sation is a smoke alarm
we call it smoke detector when you start
thinking about Blanche during meditation
that part of your mind is supposed to go
beep beep you know it's supposed to stay
just like your ties crooked or your bald
spots showing you know try to stand up
straighter
it's a monitor where you can see
yourself okay so in meditation in the
practice of meditation you're supposed
to develop a my internal monitor okay
and then when it rings an alarm
oh gosh lot you're supposed to be
meditating but you're thinking about
lunch then there's another part of your
mind which is supposed to be the tour
guide say come on this is this is not
the good part of the museum come to the
good part Museum supposed to draw you to
the better paintings you see them in our
sculptures right so the word timba means
to draw to pull you to the cool exhibit
you see the mean so you gotta have both
parts in your mind now what I'd like to
do this weekend if you want if you're
interested is apply it all day to
practice applying it all day you see I
would like to experiment with developing
these two meditational tools to run in
your mind from the time you get up till
the time you go to bed okay God is like
I would like to practice that okay but
we're studying Maha mudra okay Maha
mudra is a special kind of meditation a
very specific kind of meditation and he
his book is called the cha cha cha cha
and so on it's the most famous book on
Maha mudra it's big mother book of our
Mahamudra meditations and I would I
would like to use his book you see and
what it means is what makes a meditation
mom what makes a mom who do meditation
yeah the object of the meditation is
your own thoughts is your own mind okay
so whenever you focus your meditation on
your own mind that we give it a special
name
it's called Mohammed a meditation okay
so there's thousands of kinds of
meditations but when the object of the
meditation is the blahblah of your own
mind then that has a special name Maha
mudra and it's very high there's a very
deep tantric practice called Mohammed
and and it's there's several Mohammed or
several famous Maha mudra okay bye
the main one is watch your mind and see
if you're focusing on the first husband
or the second husband
okay Garmin at all times during
meditation watch your mind are you
focused on something that's not even
there
are you focused on something which is
there okay and and my mama went off on
this you know he taught it I remember I
remember you know he said your mind is
wrong your mind is making a mistake the
highest school of Buddhism are giving up
rocks and says you have never had a
correct perception in your life okay you
have never seen a single thing correctly
in your whole life okay
it's amazing so I'm like and then I got
upset I'm like Rimba Chang there's a
door to the toilet there's a door right
there if I open the door I get the
peepee if I don't open the door I don't
get the peepee is it the door to the
toilet or not or am I wrong he says you
wrong and I said will you want me to pee
pee in the floor the kitchen what do you
want you know what's wrong about it okay
and he said he said the coolest thing he
said it's not that you're wrong about
the door there is a door there okay got
it
there is a door there but you have a
feeling about the door that's wrong I'm
like what's the my feeling about the
door that's wrong you think the door is
coming this way but the door is coming
this way okay it's just depending okay
ignorance avidya misunderstanding the
source of all pain and Buddhism is that
it's not that you don't see doors it's
how you feel about the door and you feel
the door is coming from the door and you
don't realize the world is a pen and the
world is coming from you and you can
have anything you
if you just share what you have you seen
I mean it's if things are coming from
you then all things are possible you can
have a beautiful partner you can have as
much money as you want you can have good
health at 65 you can do ballet you know
you can have anything you want if things
are coming from you you can have
anything you want you see them in so
just try to understand that things are
coming from you now in the internal
conversation that goes on 24 hours a day
right you can you can let the devil run
loose or you can invite the angel in
okay you can let the devil run loose or
you can invite the angel in okay what's
the devil say okay you're having trouble
with somebody right somebody at work you
don't like okay there's somebody at work
that you're having trouble with okay now
I'm talking Maha mudra okay so you're
supposed to watch your mind you can do
my mudra all day especially if someone's
really irritating you
it'll be automatic you think about them
frequently okay it becomes an obsession
right it becomes the theme of your day
you know this I don't like this person
this person is irritating me okay then
the internal conversation will start now
in a normal untrained person the
misunderstanding of the irritating
person is running loose the devil has
complete control of the mind and you're
thinking of ways to get them or to stop
them or to make them embarrassed or you
know how do you know you're thinking of
different ways to get them okay the
Devils can turn your mind okay now if
the angel steps in for two minutes
what's the angel say this person's
coming from you well why you planted
them
well how you were everything
last we understand to your kids or
something and you planted this
irritating person okay got it now in
dealing with irritating people you have
now you have two choices
number one do it the old way you know
try to talk to them negotiate with them
try to get them in trouble with somebody
you know you have a whole list of things
you can try okay this is what you've
done up to now
ignore them argue with them put a banana
peel on the floor of their room you know
you have all these options come to your
mind right that the devil is it's the
million dollars ain't so much money in
Parker over here got in this just done
hello I'll keep going but you figured
out Scott says is because I hold it in
the wrong place
okay I'll try to hold it up here then if
you're lucky you go to the mahamuni talk
in Sedona and you learn to think
differently you know the angel gets five
minutes in your mind you know the angel
comes in and says look I agree the
person is an
excuse me it's everything I agree
they're irritating they really are
there's no debate about it your husband
called you stupid
I'm not saying your husband didn't card
stupid I agree your husband did a bad
thing
I agree but what we disagree about is
where it's coming from
okay if he's coming from the outside
then okay use banana peels okay fine if
he's coming from your mind if he's
coming from sins in your mind wouldn't
it be easier to just tweak a few seeds
you see what I mean okay got it got it
you see now you have a choice
once you studied Mahamudra you learn to
watch your own mind all day and your
mind when something happens that you
don't like it'll give you a choice
hey something's happening we don't like
what the doc didn't pay the million
dollars okay what do we do I think we
should write email or in Sana'a just a
devil talking you know then the good
side of your mind the Angels like wait
calm down maybe you didn't keep some
promises this week maybe if you kept
your promises you could change the speed
maybe then the guy would keep this phone
is because maybe big guys come you okay
that's the angel side okay that's the
angel if when you have a problem okay
number one when you have a problem
number two when you want something okay
I don't know my husband doesn't give me
hugs
he used to when we first got married and
then after about I don't know six months
he stopped he started hugging his laptop
more than me you know so you want
something you want more hug than you so
the devil's like okay bribe him
blackmail him you know tell them no more
dinners if you don't get hugs you know
this is the devil talking okay the devil
suggestions are only good as things were
coming this way okay but the angel
suggestions are good if things are
coming this way got it so the angel is
like no no wait give your kids more hugs
and you'll plan hug things and then
since your husband comes from you you
will get more hugs okay so the angel in
your mind is suggesting different
strategies when you're having a problem
with somebody got it and the angel in
your mind is suggesting different
strategies when you're want something
when you want to get something okay got
it
and golf okay there's a devil way of
looking at it and an ancient way of
looking and there's a devil way of
looking in an angel way of looking and
what I'm talking about that is you are
studying the most famous book ever
written about Mohammed or meditation but
I think he has phrased it as an internal
discussion because he wants you to do it
all day not not when you're sitting on
your cushion and you know then you
invite the angel in and you invite the
devil in I don't think that's the point
why did the first pension Lama one of
the greatest novels of all time why did
he phrase this teaching as an internal
discussion I think he wants you to do it
all day so that's my suggestion for this
weekend is when we do meditation
tomorrow whoever is doing meditation
yeah I mean you could pick a challenge
you have in your life or you could pick
something that you want in your life
and meditate on it tomorrow okay during
the meditation time you can you can
start a discussion in your mind vite the
angel and invite the devil okay and then
have fun okay your eyes are closed
you're indeed mahamudra meditation you
know I would like to get more hearts out
of my dark husband okay you know so then
to discuss strategies with yourself
okay discuss strategies with yourself in
your own mind
make a list okay what's the old way oh
well we would tell him no more spaghetti
dinners unless I get more heart or no
more coochie-coochie at night if I don't
get hugs all day you know this is the
devil talking okay
if things are not coming from you those
are good strategies okay if the world is
not coming
from you bribes and blackmail are good
approaches with your husband okay
if the world's not coming from you but
if the world's coming from you then
giving your kids more hugs or I don't
know be more friendly to people on the
street it's gonna plant seeds to have
your husband do what you want so then my
suggestion during meditation you can
have a conversation in your mind okay
pick one challenge in your life pick a
person is giving you trouble and pick
someone that pick something you want
like I want my money or I want I don't
know I want better health or something
like that okay and then invite the angel
and invite the devil and let him go out
you know hey you talk for a while yeah
health I heard there's a new doctor in
Sedona
she's the both Western and she's got and
she's a natural path and she's good you
know six people says she's good you know
and she's got she knows all about you
know bloodless you know extensive
supplements that she happens to sell in
the office and you know these are all
you know let your mind debate it
self-existent let the devil talk okay
then let the angel come in and excuse me
I have another suggestion of what's your
suggestion maybe we could help some sick
people maybe we can find some sick
people maybe we could just talk to
people that we know and trying to find
someone who who needs a ride to the
hospital once a week and we can give him
a ride once a week and we can plan some
health seeds and then since the health
of my body is coming from me then my
health would get better you see I mean
going to choices that's the angel by the
way talking okay the devil is like no
new supplements this is easy by vitamin
discovered in the Andes Mountains by
frogs you know and you know no and this
side here mind is like no no
you can take those that's okay but first
helps them think people you know and
then by the Frog and is stuck and it
will work you see I mean got it so what
I want you to do what I propose during
the meditation you have to think about
it you have like 12 hours to think about
it it's a lot of time in my world think
about something you want and think about
something you don't want and and let the
angel and devil talk in your mind okay
let them go at it let them have a
conversation okay and make these three
days worth something
okay you're not studying another Tibetan
book the 236 Tibetan book you study with
you know pick something you really want
or pick something you don't want and
then invite the angel and the devil into
your head and have a conversation and I
have another proposal which we're gonna
do some kind of exercise right
workshopping so you will get a partner
okay you will pair off in the afternoons
which are useless for teaching
philosophy see Mazal do something else
you care off then you be the devil and
I'll be the angel for something you are
and then we'll switch okay so if i pair
off with Qin's immuno and she says i
would like to get more hugs from my
partner or something like that you know
you have this goal so let's do a little
acting what do you call it a skit what
do you call it
role-playing yeah so you be the you mean
the devil on Albany edge are you ready
okay so what are you looking for I know
I'll be the WB the what are you looking
for what do you want you're right just
say hugs yeah so I was thinking you're
cooking every night in this guy's not
giving you hugs that is obvious what we
should do
you know just telling you too tired to
cook because he's too tired to give you
a hug good then now you're the angel
okay yeah that would work if it was
coming from him yeah something like that
you know but don't forget you're talking
to the devil you're like you gotta be
condescending yeah good idea you know
we've done that for years you know we
tried to threaten hugs out of him but
did it work
you know and yeah I want you to make in
your workshop I want you to workshop
roleplay angel demo okay
so then okay you ready no I'm the devil
you the angel okay so we you wanted hugs
right yeah so I would like to get my
million dollars
and I'm thinking to write the guy or
column or and you know send them an
email or some what do you think
today I'm double not your angel yeah I
mean kind of hot
sarcastic you know like I think they
take a picture of my stomach and then
it's just send it without any
explanation no now your angel come on
your angel yeah I mean well actually it
doesn't always work but it's what I'm
thinking about you know you see like
this
then no sooner or later she has to get
around to planting seeds okay so maybe
you should keep your promises then I'm
gonna say yeah but my promises are ten
dollar promises his promises are million
dollar fund this is how many 10 min $10
problems inside I have to keep a hundred
thousand ten dollar promises to get a
million dollars right no you're the
angel come on come on a half a gram a
corn creates a 5000 kilo tree got it
keep a few small promises yeah okay
you're not a very good angel tonight
okay so I want you guys to roleplay
tomorrow okay first you you pair off
once that angel wants a double okay and
the devil has to give stupid
self-existent solutions that don't work
and then the angel has to politely say
no I think we should do that okay then
we're gonna have a contest
angel devil contest and whoever gets the
best one gets to have extra refreshments
or less refreshments if you're on a diet
okay all right now I've been teaching
this book for eight years and if I go
through the poetry it will go very slow
so I had a new idea I'm just gonna go
through the flow of ideas I'm gonna
teach you the flow of ideas so you're
gonna get eight years review after
refreshments okay but it's gonna go like
zoom and you'll understand it and it
will come out in your workshop which
means in your life and isn't that the
whole point of it right okay
[Music]
all right but I'm not gonna be diverted
so I came home tonight they're great if
you can't sleep they put your right to
sleep so you know read the text on your
own time okay and I gave you some more
you're gonna get about 60 pages okay
all right I'm just gonna go so don't
look at the paper okay I just want to
give you a lightning review of the whole
book all right and we only have about
half an hour I'll continue tomorrow okay
and I feel better because it's been so
disjunct did it's been so irregular then
I don't think I also forgot okay all
right here we go
first is the title okay this is the long
time already this is an argument which
occurred one time between wisdom and her
opponent whose name was not the devil
it's called the tendency to think that
they think that things are real
okay and it all started when wisdom was
identified the word Mahamudra okay in
three parts of a person's left okay so
Muhammad's big mud remains seal it's a
big field that a king has to stamp
things and it's very similar to the
nuclear box codes that the American
president has okay like the king of an
ancient times was supposed to keep his
seal at hand and if because if a
document had a seal on it you know if
the document said give this person
million dollars yeah it was good if it
had the king
so this King was supposed to keep the
seal nearby and never let it get out of
his reach
okay and it certifies things that's real
emptiness angel teachings that talk
about seeds and stuff coming from you to
husbands in the kitchen teachings okay
these have the stamp of emptiness on
them which means they're certified
organic true same in fact teaching is
stamped with this idea mom mudra which
means the big step right then if it's
real if it's teaching emptiness okay so
that's basically the meaning of Maha
mudra then later mother later became a
tented word for your partner you're your
spiritual partner because you were
supposed to never let them go if they
were supposed to be like the king steel
and you never you know lose track of
them you keep them with with you time
okay right be okay
agree okay the second verse is a or
every great Buddhist book starts out by
honoring the Lamas of the lineage okay
like you can't understand these things
without her without a teacher without a
living teacher so its traditional at the
beginning of the book he honors his
teacher okay I'm just going to the verse
that's verse two okay
verse three he says all Mahamudra
practice all Great Seal practice all
Antonis practice is divided into three
parts of malaya
okay that's verse three don't look at
you don't try to read it read it at home
okay all right now first stage which is
verse four okay we have to do 100
verse four there's a natural Mahamudra
which is the natural state of your mind
which is that when you were bored you
started to believe that things were
coming this way okay that's called not
natural Mahamudra and it's called a
natural error it's a natural error of
the mind the mind believes when you're
born as fish birds you know donkeys they
all believe things are coming this way
it's a natural part of living beings
mind okay it's called natural Mahamudra
a natural mistake that we all make okay
and as long as you make that mistake you
have the devil in your mind and as long
as you are trying to solve the problems
in your life that right you will always
have troubles okay you will never solve
the problems in your mind they will keep
coming back okay because they're coming
from you but you don't know all right
verse five misunderstanding that things
come from you is the source of all human
suffering from breaking a fingernail up
to nuclear destruction all trouble in
the world is caused by thinking that
things are coming this way when they're
actually coming this way that's verse by
verse 6 the only thing that can stop
human suffering is to understand that
things are coming from you okay
verse 6 I'm just giving you you can read
the verses at home okay now there's
another version first 7 there's a second
version of not
so Mahamudra which is called a clear
line of death okay
when you die as you go through the
process of dying the inner winds reaches
data rest at which it's a very good
chance to try to see emptiness okay so
every human being once in their life is
very close to emptiness by accident and
it's at a certain stage in the death
process okay so that's also that's
called secondary natural maha-mantra
during the death process I like to say
it's like a New York subway and they
slow down right before they get to 4th
Street Station or something and then you
have a few minutes to get on and then it
takes off again so every person every
creatures mind even animals as they die
the train slows down for a few minutes
and if you know what you're doing but
it's very hard to do okay anyway that's
it also called the clean line of my
first verse eight that you can learn to
use that clear light without dying if
you learn to do Mahmud mudra meditation
okay so there is a meditation where you
learn to do what you can do and death
okay both of those are called path Maha
mudra okay so there's there's a way to
take the natural Maha mudra of the mind
and jump use it as a path okay as a as a
way to get happiness in your life okay
number nine the ultimate path Maha mudra
okay the second kind of mine would be
right first is natural second is path
path is you can do specific meditations
to get the devil out of your mind
okay there are specific meditations that
make it too hot inside your head
for the devil to stay okay and that's
the goal of this book you know we're
gonna try to learn certain kinds of
meditation that make it impossible for
the devil to talk in your head imagine
that Geshe Michael can stand in front of
the fridge and look at one of Veronica's
cakes and not think you know a million
dollars not so much money you understand
like you can what do you call lobotomy
you can cut that part of your brain out
okay you can make your brain pure with
these meditations okay number ten when
you get really good in Mahamudra and you
can see emptiness directly we call it
the path off scene okay and it's short
it's like 20 minutes it takes many years
to get there and it changes your whole
being okay now you can consolidate that
understanding and make it part of your
life and that's called the path of
habituation and that's when you start
using your knowledge of emptiness in the
kitchen who's going to tell me where's
the emptiness in the kitchen
Scott good yeah in a single one okay
that the irritating person in the
kitchen who decided to yell at me is not
there and was never there okay could not
be there okay no one in your life ever
hurt you
no one no such thing okay in this system
they came from you they came because you
said something to your kids yesterday
okay got it so that's called path of
habituation you get used to emptiness so
don't think it's some kind of mystery
don't close your eyes and try to think
about nothing
that's all complete hogwash see I don't
have to use bad words it's just
ridiculous
okay has nothing to do with emptiness
emptiness means the husband in the
kitchen who's not coming from you was
never there
that's all forget everything else you
heard about emptiness it's all wrong
okay if you understand emptiness
correctly you will be a happy
well-rounded successful person that's
all okay if you understand that the guy
yelling at you in the kitchen who's not
coming from you was never there you're
gonna be a well-adjusted person and
that's all you'll be a super happy
person and you'll be you can make weird
things happy you can make people make
million-dollar bets with you if you lose
twenty pounds you see I mean you can
make weird stuff happen I was talking
about this in wasn't Ukraine Russia I
don't remember and I got a text and I
looked down at the text and I told the
translator you read that text the
audience and the text was from John
Brady I told him to go to Vietnam and
ask some rich lady for million dollars
and she said yes and there was a photo
of John life and for our College as a
donation to our College so I said look
did I just get this message she says yes
I said read it to the audience so I just
made a million dollars okay we just made
a million dollars just now you know and
if you understand emptiness you can make
weird stuff happen okay then it doesn't
become weird anymore
okay got it you can even make your
husband hug you all right which is
harder than a million dollars okay okay
next one there's a part called verse 12
okay there's a part called the pattern
no more learning that's where you reach
nirvana and that's defined as no one
can upset you okay no one can upset you
cuz you just laugh at them and say
you're not real you're not coming from
me you are you are fake you're a fake
husband you know
you're not a real husband you know you
can say anything you want I don't care
okay
got it say yes if you don't say yes I'll
make you stay here I'll go home okay all
right last one and if you keep that up
in the kitchen with the husband your
body will change into a rainbow body and
you become a Buddha and you're able to
emanate to countless worlds in in a few
minutes time and help countless beings
at the same time okay if you keep
actively with knowledge shutting up in
the kitchen it actually transforms your
body okay if you do it long enough your
body changes and you become a being who
can help a billion beings at the same
time and that's what you really want you
know that's what you were born to do
right that's born
I keep thinking Steppenwolf born to be
born to be Buddha okay like you were
built for that and you know it and you
always wanted it and you're hungry for
it you want to serve the entire universe
at the same time that's your super inner
dream you know everybody has it and if
you keep up on a day-to-day
moment-to-moment basis that kitchen
behavior you cannot prevent your body
from changing into an angel it's not
possible to stop it you will become an
angel
okay cool got it now segue time segue
time in the poem in this epic poem which
I believe will become whether the world
spiritual classics once it's translated
well it's really on the level of Dante
Shakespeare I mean it is it really is
but it's more meaningful you know then
there's a segue okay which is very
clever the first pencil Evans clever
okay and he says those Buddha bodies
that you're gonna get because you
understand the husband in the kitchen
they are unreal they're also coming from
your mind the body that you're gonna
achieve the the hopes of your whole life
that party isn't real okay because
that's body which serves people on a
billion planets is also coming from 65
seats a second from your head if the
body's not real okay got it
and to think it's real is the biggest
mistake a human mind can make okay to
look down at your body and say this was
given to me by my mother and this is
made of chemicals and and it has to die
this is to think that way is the biggest
mistake a human being can make okay
that's verse 14 okay 15 okay
now therefore the disa prayer may I
forever
banish this kind of thinking from my
mind may I never believe that my
husband's yelling at me cuz he wants to
may I always understand that it's coming
from me
may I root out the mental cancer are
believing that people are coming this
way may I rip it out of my mind
okay got it this is how the flow of the
text next verse that part oh yeah that
part of the guy's mind says whoa wait a
minute wait a minute you don't want to
get rid of that part of your mind this
not so bad
got it the the part of the mind that he
wants to lobotomy what do you call it
exercise that part of the mind stands up
and says whoa wait a minute
I have judge then the debate starts then
the book starts it's so beautiful okay
how did we segue there somebody tell me
what I did in Ukraine I always put five
hundred dollars on it for five hundred
dollars no but what was just before the
biggest mistake yeah you're gonna have a
rainbow party Wow you know you're gonna
have a rainbow buddy and if you think
that body is real that's the biggest
mistake you can make
okay got it if you think it doesn't come
from your seat if you think you can't
make a body like that that's the biggest
mistake you have let us all permanently
you know cut this surgically cut this
kind of thinking from our mind and then
there's this objection from whom that
part of the guy's brains is bull slow
down
you don't want to cut this part of your
brain out okay and then the fight starts
okay and it goes on for many many pages
it's a glorious fight okay but the guy
stands out who's the guy
yeah he know that part of your mind
who believes the husband is bad and the
husband has to be spoken to you know
that part of the mind stands up says
whoa wait a minute
okay now verse 16 wait a minute verse 17
I have been your constant companion for
your
okay I'm part of who you are okay like I
always took care of you your whole life
without me
your husband will go Wow you would say
anything you know I have always watched
out for your best interest
it sounds like a senatorial debate on
the radio I've always watched out from
you you know you don't want to kick me
out of office I took care of you you
know this is the the devil it's like
I've been here forever you can't cut me
out of your mind you're gonna cut your
whole mind up you know okay first
eighteen I'm like your father I'm like
your mother who fed you your old who got
you your clothes who got you your car
who got you your house competition
fighting for what's your right this
sounds just like that debate I heard the
debate on the radio it sounded just you
I'm the one who stood up for you
you know without self-interest who's
gonna feed you who's gonna get you
things I've been like your mother I've
been like a father I got you every
possession you have you can't get rid of
me
okay got it it's very beautiful
okay and I brought you to the real three
jewels desire hatred and ignorance
okay got it like he corrupted everything
three jewels is the Buddhist Trinity
right father son Holy Ghost we say
Buddha Dharma in the community right the
teaching the teacher and the community
these are the holiest things in in
Buddhism Lama pelmet created the three
jewels in New York right she called her
when 25 years ago 27 years ago Outreach
Center okay it's called the three jewels
this guy says I'm the one who brought
you the Holy Dharma of the three poisons
okay the three animals at the center of
the wheels left right pig rooster and
snake snake is anger biggest ignorance
under rooster is desire okay got it
he's corrupting and it's kind of weird I
read a book you should read a book by CS
Lewis great Christian writer called the
Screwtape Letters and he wrote it during
World War two and it is letters of
advice from the devil to his nephew
who's been assigned to corrupt a young
man you know and then he keeps messing
up and the young man keeps going to
church and stuff you see and then the
devil's like sends him suggestions how
to get him out of the church and how to
stop him from praying and then after he
wrote the book CS Lewis had an extended
period of depression and he said to put
my mind in the Dallas mind was painful
you know to write those letters of evil
was painful to my mind you know and this
is very similar and see the pension lama
has to think of what the devil would say
and he has to write
and I can imagine it with distasteful
right anyway here we go now the angel of
wisdom makes her appearance over here I
don't think his million dollars is such
a lot of money who's that
I guess it's the devil and then she's
like come on let's talk okay ready verse
20 she makes her first appearance okay
wisdom okay who understands the two
husbands and the pen okay but the woman
who who goes oh I don't want my kids to
act up next with my husband is a fool
but I won't say it okay got it got it
wisdom appears in the mind and now the
debate starts okay see how the flow is
got the flow he's like you can't get rid
of me I don't care who's gonna who's
gonna make you selfish if I don't you
know who's gonna make you get things for
you
who's gonna help you to watch out for
number one without me you know you let
this angel take over you're gonna end up
giving away own stuff what's wrong with
you okay got it
all right she says excuse me where where
have you stayed my whole life and the
devil says in your mind and she says
mind what mine there is no mine
okay got it she's like very innocently
she says you've been in my mind what's
that where's that it's like right man
you know where you think know that
that's just something that comes from my
scene got it what you see as your home
is the second
who's she talking to the devil okay
he it gets hard enough in the first few
lines got it I'll say it again the angel
shows up and says oh you've been in my
mind the whole time you deserve to stay
you've been taking care of me well
what's the address of my mind with the
mind come from cuz he can't get it so
when you hear a thought in your mind it
is popping out of what you said to
people last week okay you don't have
cards you are listening to them you are
the listener who's thinking them they're
just popping out of karma they're
popping like the pen picture but thought
pictures okay garlic she understands
that the devil doesn't even understand
where he lives
okay she's like you don't live in my
mind I do
what's my mind it's the one who are you
seeing
I don't think thoughts pop out of comics
things from what I did last week
there's no mind there's no house where
you live that where your second husband
house got him
just say yes I mean he doesn't mess
around
he jumps right in okay oh you seen my
mic no you don't
okay got it and by the way who's you
anyway okay who's that you who stays in
my mind okay
my mind is socks breaking out of karmic
seeds in my mind I don't think those
thoughts I'd listen to them they are
presented to me when I get depressed I
have to be depressed because I heard
someone last week you see I have
depressed thoughts popping out of mine
I'm just
listening to them you can't stop a scene
from opening you see I mean God then she
says and by the way who are you this
living in my mind do you where do you
come from and he thinks he comes from
his side
he doesn't realize it's coming from his
own seat you see I mean even the devil
in your mind doesn't understand what he
is got him right off she attacks him she
blazed a boom
she's like innocently right this is
perfect debate style oh you're in my
mind oh where do you mind okay got it
she's like attacking him there's a joke
what's his writers famous writer kill
them with smiles and drown them with
yeses okay anyway okay okay where am i
come from okay got it
it's very beautiful I think so anyway
okay then the devil okay you gotta
listen to the devil's response they will
stop for tonight
by the way there's heavy stuff in the
first few pages and then it gets worse
okay then she says oh this is devil now
devil talking back to the angel he's not
a stupid demo the best Devils are clever
okay real Devils are clever he's like oh
so I don't exist
oh you belong to that nihilist school
you're the school that says everything's
empty so nothing exists
oh is it I've been waiting to meet one
of you guys okay this is a classic enemy
of Buddhism okay who misinterprets
emptiness and says if things are empty
that nothing matters and I can do what I
want okay it's a corrupt view point of
emptiness that says if if the husband is
not in the kitchen right then I can kill
people I can still think it doesn't
matter it's all empty are you here dance
sometimes you know I'm above morality
I understand emptiness okay then he's
like Oh miss angel you must be in that
school right because you say I don't
exist got it
oh gee I thought I was dependently
originating I thought you Buddhist way
around saying things come from Carlton
oh excuse me
you know I didn't know angels thought we
don't think they're the things darling
got it
it's a classic misunderstanding and
emptiness to say if things aren't empty
they don't exist she accused him of not
existing right so he says back to her oh
gee I thought you were Buddhist but
you're just most people says the
emptiness means nothing oh okay got it
somebody not Chintamani right okay he's
being sarcastic back to her oh you're
not a good you think emptiness means
there's no husband at all right because
you just accused me of not existing in a
brain that didn't exist
good okay then he says but may I quote
to you Buddhism I don't exist ultimately
but I exist nominally in projections I'm
coming from seizing your mind I it's not
that I don't exist I'm dependent
origination
okay got it
all right it should be you should be
wrong if you're a real Buddhist you
should be that okay never mind
okay now here's his final thing and for
$200 somebody's gonna tell me what's up
okay ready
that's how you get people listening it's
gotta okay I'll pay you back tomorrow
for sure okay now here's the devil
stalking oh you want me to leave the
mine you want me to leave this house you
want me to be the one to leave well
actually I'm the person who believes
that things exist two projections but
that's my position got it now you're the
one who has to leave because you say
nothing exists in and of itself you say
nothing exists self-existent Lee so I
think you will have to leave because I
am mr. dependent origination
so we're incompatible we can't stand the
same apartment you'll have to go I'm
sorry I'll say it again ready
I'm mr. dependent origination I believe
in
the devil has come from seeds and I'm
surprised that you would take a position
that nothing exists okay got it
he's very sophisticated but you know
because you believe nothing exists
ultimately if you will have to leave the
mind okay I don't give money to anybody
now listen listen you give me a good
answer you can go home and me too he
believes things are coming from karmic
seeds dependent origination okay it was
the the husband comes from the kids
right dependent origination got it she
believes the second husband doesn't
exist the one who didn't come from me
does one of them have to leave the
kitchen No okay garden he's trying to
trick us I'll say it again he supports
the idea that the husband is coming from
how I treated my kids and he says
unfortunately we can't stand the kitchen
together because you believe the husband
who didn't come from the seed doesn't
exist but is it true that they can't
stay in the same kitchen they have to
stay in the same kitchen who said that
that's worth $100 okay I owe you 100 all
right that answer is worth 100 that's a
leg so leg so sit down sit down correct
answer she said they have to live in the
kitchen together okay garlic emptiness
and dependent origination must get
married and they must live in the same
kitchen got it he's twisting everything
oh you believe nothing's this I believe
everything's this you have to live
please garden does she believe nothing
is this
a certain way she does things that are
not coming from you are not in the
kitchen but does that mean there's no
first husband in the kitchen no of
course not they get along the Scot and
word are friends okay right aren't you
pretty much gari Scott doesn't not come
from nothing doesn't come from nothing
nothing okay and word comes from
something and they can they can live
quite well together got it
so the devil is already trying to screw
things up got it it's really cool it's
really cool now you want some
controversy
she says dependent origination does not
exist even nominally she says the angel
says the fact that word came from the
kids sees right that also doesn't exist
even even as a projection doesn't exist
true or false false everything exists as
a projection okay but she says cause and
effect do do not come from me that's her
answer she starts from there but you
have to come tomorrow to find out why
she's not completely wrong I'll say it
again
she says you think things come from
causes from seed from how you treat
other
she says no not even as a projection not
true okay got it
now that's a very bad position okay it's
a very wrong position but she takes it
now to find out where she's going with
it you have to come tomorrow okay let's
do a mandala is that okay Janice you
might do Mendoza
loud yeah now this is an offering of a
perfect world to celebrate the teaching
it's a tradition that's all
think of the world there's no more
Devils in the whole room
the sungazing do they don't she not sure
you don't go to
she she
[Music]
okay good